

Abusufyan Sher

Backend Developer | DBA

Contact

shersufyan@gmail.com

+923329710685

🡤 🛮 Mardan, KP, Pakistan

in/abusufyansher1

Programming Languages

- Laravel Framework
- Codelgnitor Framework
- OOP PHP
- C#
- ASP.Net Core MVC (Basics)
- JavaScript
- Python (Basics)
- MySQL & SQL Server
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Bootstrap
- WordPress

Languages

- English
- Urdu
- Pashto



Profile

An experienced web base application developer with more then 4+years of experience, motivated individual with in-depth knowledge of languages and development tools, seeking a position in a growth-oriented company where I can use my skills to the advantage of the company while having the scope to develop my own skills



Education

Bachelor (Honors) in Computer Science (Software)

Abdul Wali Khan University Mardan (2020)

3.73/4.00 - Gold Medal (1st Distinction)

Research Topic:

Face Recognition for Authorization of Driver's Drowsiness Detection for Surveillance



Experience

Abdul Wali Khan University Mardan

Programmer BPS-17

(Sept 2021 - Present)

Responsibilities

- Development & deployment of CMS on Server
- APIs integrations with Bank of Khyber
- Database Development & Management
- Custom Softwares Development
- Advance reporting for HEC & HED

Pakhtunkhwa Economic Policy Research Institute

Programmer

(Dec 2020 - June 2021)

Responsibilities

- Worked on DB Management & software development
- Developed PEPRI's website using Laravel
- Developed Database for the "JAEBS"
- API Integration with different indexing organizations
- Administering of computer networking for DRC

SpaceLink IT Solutions Mardan

Junior Software Developer

(Oct 2018 - Nov 2020)

Responsibilities

• Coding software, and helping the QA team to test software before release.

Internee

(April 2018 - Sept 2018)

Responsibilities

- Developing applications and approaching problem with solutions
- Collaborating with seniors



Technical Skills

- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Database Design
- Relational Databases
- Advance SQL Query
- Source Version Control (Git/GitHub)
- Networking Basics
- SDLC (Software Development Life Cycle)

- Software Requirement Engineering
- MS Excel
- Object Oriented Design (OOD)
- Code Testing and Debugging
- Web Applications Deployment on Cpanel, CWP, WHM
- Virtual Machine
- RestFul API Development



Soft Skills

- Problem Solving and Logical Thinking
- Good analytical skills
- Team player and good interpersonal skills
- Ability to perform under stress and aggressive deadlines
- Self-organized with the ability to plan ahead
- Excellent communication skills
- Flexible timings
- Inquisitiveness



Projects

- AWKUM University Management System (UMS) https://lms.awkum.edu.pk
- AWKUM Online Admissions System (OAS) https://admissions.awkum.edu.pk
- AWKUM Testing Service (ATS) Deployed on Local Server
- AWKUM Alumni https://alumni.awkum.edu.pk
- HRM https://career.awkum.edu.pk
- PEPRI https://pepri.edu.pk
- SciFoci http://scifoci.com/
- Real Estate Management System https://crm.zainmarketing.com.pk/
- E-Campus Mgt System http://smartlmskp.com/
- Jbt (Research Journal) http://jbt.org.pk/
- The Discourse http://discourse.org.pk/
- Noumania Foundation https://noumaniafoundation.org/
- Zaviyar Enterprises https://zaviyarenterprises.com/
- International Journal of Agricultural and Economic Research https://ijaaer.com/
- Center for economic policy an sustainability sciences https://cepps.org
- Club Interface https://clubinterface.idamru.net/
- Face recognition and Authentication using Python
- · QR Code Attendance System
- Point Of Sale



Achievement

- Gold Medalist in Bachelor Degree
- Certificate and Shield of appreciation from Rector of AWKUM for development of LMS During Covid-19
- Gold Medal at Mardan Science Exhibition
- Gold Medal of AWKUM Glowing Stars



Invited Talk

- Invited talked at AI-NAVTCC- AWKUM on "Web Technologies & Emergency Industrial Tool"
- Invited talked at AWKUMTECH on "Search Engine Optimization"